tate.org.uk 2017-06-06

# Tate website privacy notice and use of cookies | Tate

## Privacy and cookies

Respecting your privacy and security is very important to us. Tate is committed to protecting your personal information.  This policy sets out the basis upon which information is collected about you by Tate and its associated company through the use of the Tate website and any other electronic communications networks by Tate and the use of the personal information you provide to us in person or online, via email, phone, in writing or other correspondence.  For example, your personal information may be collected or provided by submissions to our website, use of our mobile applications, purchase of exhibition tickets, joining as a member and using your membership card, purchases and telephone calls to or from us, competition entries, emails, correspondence, events and event booking, fundraising or campaign responses.  We do not collect or process sensitive personal data such as race ethnic origin, physical or mental health, political or philosophical views or sexual orientation.  Please read the policy carefully as by providing your personal data to Tate and/or TEL you will be deemed to have consented to the processing of such data.

### Who we are

The Board of Trustees of the Tate Gallery (‘Tate’) exists to promote the public’s enjoyment and understanding of British art from the sixteenth century to the present day and of international modern and contemporary art. Tate is an exempt charity under the Charities Act 2011. Tate’s principal place of business is at Millbank, London SW1P 4RG. Tate Enterprises Limited (company number 3173975) (‘TEL’) is a wholly owned subsidiary of Tate which trades on Tate’s behalf and exists to support Tate.  Under this policy, ‘we’ and ‘Tate’ refers to both Tate and TEL.

We will never sell, rent or exchange your details with any other organisation outside the Tate group.

## 1\. Information collected

When you use the Tate website, we may collect personal information about you when you request a specific service using online forms and every time you email us your details. We use this information to:

  * contact you to respond to your queries (if you email us with a question, for example)
  * provide you with services (send you an email bulletin or enable your progress through an online course, for example)
  * personalise your experience of Tate content (remembering your most recent search in [Art & artists](http://www.tate.org.uk/art/), for example)
  * contact you to ask you to respond to surveys
  * optimise your experience of Tate content (remembering your connection speed to serve you streamed video, for example)

We collect information about you when you comment or create user accounts and log in to the following website services:

We collect information about you when you use a Tate checkout to buy the following products:

We collect information about you in the following ways:

  * When you join as a Member, purchase a ticket or make a donation;
  * When you are purchased a gift membership by another person;
  * When you use your membership card(s); 
  * When you make purchases in the Tate shop in one of our galleries or online;
  * When you create online user accounts and online checkouts;
  * When you sign up and respond to Tate emails;
  * When you sign in to use Wifi on your visits;
  * When you download and use Tate apps;
  * When you book the restaurants;
  * When you provide feedback or send us an e-mail

### Signing in using social networking credentials

If you sign in to our sites using a Facebook sign in as a means of authentication, you grant permission to Facebook to share your user details. This will include your name and email address which will then be used to form a Tate Digital account. Please be aware that this authentication also permits the sharing of your gender, date of birth, user ID, networks, location and any other information you may choose to share according to your Facebook account settings. If you remove the Tate app from your Facebook settings, then our access to your additional information will cease. For more information, visit [Facebook’s App Privacy Settings & Your Info](http://www.facebook.com/help/262314300536014/) page.

If you sign in to our sites using a Google sign in as a means of authentication, you grant permission to Google to share your user details. This will include your name and email address, date of birth, gender and location which will then be used to form a Tate Digital account. Please be aware that this authentication also permits the sharing of your public profile URL, photo, gender, date of birth, country, language, and timezone according to your Google account settings. If you remove Tate from your Google settings, then our access to your additional information will cease. For more information, visit [Google’s Authorizing applications and sites](https://support.google.com/accounts/topic/2665423?hl=en&ref_topic=2399170) page.

If you sign in to our sites using a Twitter sign in as a means of authentication, we receive your Twitter username. For more information, visit [Twitter’s Connecting or revoking third-party applications](https://support.twitter.com/articles/76052-how-to-connect-and-revoke-third-party-applications) page.

## 2\. Use of cookies

Cookies are pieces of data that a website can transfer to an individual’s computer hard drive for record keeping. Cookies can make websites easier to use by storing information about your preferences on a particular website. The information may remain on your computer after the Internet session finishes and you leave the website but you can delete them using some browsers, manually or using system utilities. Most internet browsers are pre-set to accept cookies.

If you prefer not to receive cookies, you can adjust your internet browser to refuse cookies or to warn you when cookies are being used. This site will work more efficiently if receipt of cookies is enabled but it will still operate correctly if you disable cookies.

For more information on cookies and their uses, visit [All About Cookies](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

### 2.1 Google Analytics

We use [Google Analytics](http://www.google.co.uk/intl/en/analytics/privacyoverview.html) to collect information about how our visitors use and navigate this website. We use this information to report to funders such as the [Department for Culture, Media and Sport](http://www.culture.gov.uk/) and to analyse usage of the website so that we can continually work to add new features and improve your experience of it.

The cookies collect information such as the number of visitors to the site, which pages they visited and whereabouts they came to the site from. This information is anonymous and cannot be used to identify you personally.

### 2.2 Personalised advertising

If you browse this website you may receive personalised banner advertisements whilst browsing other reputable websites. We are committed to providing you with information on products and offers which are relevant to you. The banner advertisements will relate to exhibition pages, events or products which have been viewed whilst browsing this website on your computer or other device.

This service is provided by Tate via reputable third-party specialist companies like Sizmek, DataXu and Quantcast, through the use of cookies placed on your computer or other device. These companies may choose to target you based on your Non-Personally Identifiable Information (Non-PII), this includes but is not limited to IP host address, the date and time of activity online, the pages viewed, browser type, referring URL, Internet Service Provider and operating system. These companies do not collect Personally Identifiable Information (PII) such as name, address, phone number, email, address, credit card information or anything else that can personally identify you.

You can visit these individual companies and read their privacies for more information on how to opt out. [The Sizmek privacy policy](http://www.sizmek.com/privacy-policy/), [Quantcast privacy policy](https://www.quantcast.com/privacy/) and [Data Xu privacy policy](https://www.dataxu.com/about-us/privacy/) are all available online. 

You may also opt out of receiving further personalised advertisements in the future by clicking on the bottom right hand corner of any advertisement you receive and following the instructions.

### 2.3 Third-party cookies

During your visits to the Tate website you may be delivered cookies by third-party websites. When you visit a page with content embedded from, for example, Facebook, SoundCloud, Vimeo, Twitter, YouTube, Google Maps or Flickr, you may be presented with cookies from these websites. Tate does not control the dissemination of these cookies. You should check the third-party websites for more information about these.

### 2.4 Website Behaviour Tracking Cookies

We use a technology called Silverpop which allows us to track a person’s behaviour on this website if they have clicked though to our website from an email sent by Tate or if they have signed up to receive emails while visiting this website. The website behaviour tracking cookies would only be enabled once you opt in to receive emails and the cookies will expire in accordance with the description in the table below. We will share information about your visit to our website with Silverpop, which will only be attributed to your email address. Tate will use the information for reporting and to monitor the effectiveness of our marketing applications. Tate will also use this information to find out more about your interests and tailor email content to you accordingly.

This table lists the type of cookies that we use on your computer and what behavioural information is being tracked:

### 2.5 Surveys

We run regular surveys to improve our website. Cookies are used to allow the form or pop-up survey to be hidden on your return visits. This is to prevent you from being shown the survey again unnecessarily. Cookies are also used to record the overall number of answers to the survey questions and to link these to web statistics. They do not store your personal data.

### 2.6 Tate Members

#### Data use

When you join as a Tate Member we collect information about you in order to:

  * send your membership benefits by post i.e. your membership welcome pack and cards, magazine and Guide etc
  * provide you with services (i.e. send you an email bulletin or SMS)
  * talk to you about Tate Enterprises and Tate Foundation (i.e. notification of Tate shop discounts and fundraising communication about our charitable work)
  * personalise your experience of Tate (i.e. to build a picture of your interests which means we can tell you about programme and product offerings that are most relevant to your interests)

Where adequate measures have been taken to anonymise your personal data, for example by way of a cryptographic hash function, this data may be provided to third parties to process lawfully and in accordance with any consents you have previously given.

We do not collect or process sensitive personal data such as race, ethnic origin, physical or mental health, political or philosophical views or sexual orientation. We will never sell, rent or exchange your details with any other organisation.

#### Working with suppliers

In some cases we work with external suppliers to provide certain services. All data is transferred securely and all external suppliers have signed data processing and confidentiality agreements with Tate.

#### Privacy and data protection

Tate complies with all applicable UK and EU data protection legislation in force in respect of any personal information you submit to us. The personal data you submit to us will only be used for the specified purposes indicated to you and will not be passed onto unauthorised third parties without your explicit consent.   Please note that for technical reasons, we may sometimes need to use the services of a supplier outside the European Economic Area (‘EEA’) and transfer your personal data to countries outside the EEA that may not have the same level of data protection as countries within the EEA.  However, if we intend to do this, before any transfer takes place we will put in place contractual arrangements to ensure that there is adequate protection of your data and that these comply with European data protection regulations. You can contact us to amend or remove any information you submit to us – please call + (44) 20 7887 8888 or email [members@tate.org.uk](mailto:members@tate.org.uk). You can unsubscribe from emails by clicking on the relevant ‘unsubscribe’ link in Members’ emails.

## 3\. Other websites

Our website may contain links to other websites which are outside our control and are not covered by this privacy notice. If you access other sites using the links provided, the operators of these sites may collect information from you which will be used by them in accordance with their privacy policy, which may differ from ours.

## 4\. Apps privacy policy

Our [Privacy Policy](http://www.tate.org.uk/about/business-services/tate-publishing/apps-privacy-policy) explains what we do with the information we collect through our apps. Tate cares about your privacy and aims to comply with The Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA). If you have any questions about our apps or our privacy policy, please contact [apps@tate.org.uk](mailto:apps@tate.org.uk).

## 5\. Changes to this privacy notice

From time to time Tate may change this privacy notice. You may therefore wish to check this page each time you submit personal information to Tate. The latest privacy notice will always appear on this page.

## 6\. Contacting Tate about this privacy notice

If you have any questions or comments about this privacy notice, please contact us at [webmaster@tate.org.uk](mailto:webmaster@tate.org.uk).
